Finding Aid for [Freshman-sophomore rush posters, University of Michigan], 1883?-1941
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
[Freshman-sophomore rush posters, University of Michigan] 1883?-1941
University of Michigan.
37 items in 2 folders
Broadside FImu F97
Posters and broadsides concerning competition between freshman and sophomore classes at the university of Michigan
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The poster collection was assembled from a number of sources.
No further to the collection are expected.
The collection is open without restriction.
Competition between classes was a feature of student life from the early days of the university. I particular between the freshman and sophomore classes as the sophomores sought to initiate the incoming freshman to campus life. The competition expressed itself in hazing, a variety of pranks, athletic competition, and a "rush" which generally involved one class defending some symbolic object or piece of campus against the attack of the other class. "Black Friday" was one of the main expressions of the competition. On an designated Friday in the Fall the freshman would gather around the campus flagpole to defend their banner against the sophomores/ The battle would continue until the sophomores had captured the banner or the freshman had defended it for at least thirty minutes.
The collections consists of 37 poster (21 freshman class and 16 sophomore class) ranging in date from the sophomore class of 1886 to the sophomore class of 1944. The posters are listed by class year--the year a freshman class would graduate. Thus the class of 1910 poster marks the Black Friday event of the Fall of 1906.
Subjects:
University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs.; University of Michigan--Freshmen.; University of Michigan--Sophomores.
Genre Terms:
Posters.
- Freshman Posters (Folder 2)
  - Class of 1903 -- Come early and don't avoid the rush
  - Class of 1908 -- Man the gun
  - Class of 1908 -- Declaration of war
  - Class of 1909 -- Attention sophomores declaration of war
  - Class of 1909 -- War is declared!
  - Class of 1910 -- We're going to win the rush
  - Class of 1910 -- Black Friday October 5, 1906
  - Class of 1911 -- 'S blood 's death to ye soph
  - Class of 1911 -- Sophies! Ye slimy, sulking scullions of 1910 hearken!
  - Class of 1911 -- Hear yez!!!
  - Class of 1911 -- From the slums of bog and fen comes the class of naughty ten.
  - Class of 1912 -- Ye dethe sentence
  - Class of 1912 -- Behave ye blubbering soph
  - Class of 1912 -- Ovez! Oyez! Oyez!
  - Class of 1912 -- Witches' chorus
  - Class of 1926 -- Yea '26 Be it known
  - Class of 1936 -- Here lies a bed of sophomores
  - Class of 1938 -- Attune your senses sophs
  - Class of 1941 -- Warning issued by class of '41 Beware sophs
  - Class of 1941 -- Beware sophs
  - Class of 1942 -- Ultimatum to the class of '41
- Sophomore Posters (Folder 2)
  - Class of 1886 -- Attention freshies!
  - Class of 1906 -- Oh! Joy! Freshman blood
  - Class of 1907 -- 1908 1908
  - Class of 1908 -- Black Friday October 6, 1905
  - Class of 1909 -- Ye fresh man attention
  - Class of 1910 -- Ha ha yield freshmen
  - Class of 1911 -- Frosh! Stop! Look! Listen!
  - Class of 1911 -- Stop look read freshmen
  - Class of 1914 -- Hark! You sapheads
  - Class of 1915 -- Hist puny frosh
  - Class of 1930 -- It's your neck! '31
  - Class of 1931 -- Frosh! Thy doom approacheth
  - Class of 1932 -- Proclamation to ye infantile frosh
  - Class of 1933 -- Frosh -- on the spot
  - Class of 1934 -- Beware Frosh!
  - Class of 1944 -- 0 ye scribblers of '45